Guide to the Abraham Joshua Heschel Papers, 1880, 1919-1998 and undated RL.10086
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1880, 1921-1990s and undated; 6; 245 Boxes
  - Books, circa 1930s-1990s and undated; 9
    - The Prophets, circa 1930s-1971 and undated; 11
      - Prophets לא חשוב: לא חשוב, 1958, 1960; 1 of 2 (Box 153, Folder 5)
        Transliteration: Lo Ḥashuv: Lo Ḥashuv
        Translation: Not important: Not important
        Handwritten notes related to The Prophets. Topics include idolatry, psychology, anger, separation, Jeremiah, Isaiah, Amos, Ezekiel and divination.
      - Prophets לא חשוב: לא חשוב, 1958, 1960; 2 of 2 (Box 153, Folder 6)
      - Prophets לא חשוב: ישעיה ב, 1959 (Box 153, Folder 7)
        Transliteration: Lo Ḥashuv: Yeshaʻyah B
        Translation: Not important: Isaiah 2
        Handwritten notes related to The Prophets, particularly about the prophet Isaiah.
      - Prophets: [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s (Box 153, Folder 8)
        Handwritten notes consisting primarily of quotes and citations.
      - Prophets: Formalism, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 153, Folder 9)
        Contains handwritten notes related to prophets. Also includes a typescript outlining the organization of Die Prophetie and Heschel's approach to the treatise.
      - Prophet: [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s-1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 154, Folder 1)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes on a variety of topics including the prophets Isaiah, Jeremiah, and Amos and other theological topics such as pity and inwardness. Some of the notes are marked "out" in pencil.
      - Prophet: [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s-1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 154, Folder 2)
      - Prophet: [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s-1960s; 3 of 3 (Box 154, Folder 3)
      - Prophets: [Miscellaneous notes], circa 1950s-1960s (Box 154, Folder 4)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes related to a variety of topics including spirit, sympathy, and ecstasy.
      - אין שני נביאים בסגנון אחד: Prophets, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 154, Folder 5)
        Transliteration: En Sheni Neviʼim be-Signon Eḥad
        Translation: The Are No Two Prophets In The Same Style
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes, mostly on various themes related to the prophets and their reception; Being. Seem to be preparatory work possibly related to The Prophets.
      - שונות: Prophets, 1961-1962 (Box 154, Folder 6)
        Primarily handwritten notes, presumably research material related to The Prophets. Also contains offprint of HaNevuah v'Giluyah by Judah Dabir.
      - [Galley Proof - The Prophets], 1962 (Box 154, Folder 7)
        An annotated galley proof of the first couple pages of The Prophets.
      - הוספות: Prophets, 1962 (Box 154, Folder 8)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes primarily on the topic of pathos. Also includes typed excerpts from Chapter 24 of God in Search of Man and correspondence from Annabel Learned regarding corrected proofs of The Prophets.
      - Prophets: Preface, 1962 (Box 155, Folder 1)
        Mix of handwritten notes and typescripts related to the preface of The Prophets.
      - Prophets: UTS, 1962 (Box 155, Folder 2)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes related to The Prophets, primarily on the topic of pathos. The notes appear to be written when Heschel was conducting research at UTS. Also includes a letter from James Muilenburg of UTS to publisher Harper and Brothers outlining concerns he has with Heschel's manuscript.
      - Prophets, 1962-1963 (Box 155, Folder 3)
        Mostly correspondence from admirers and colleagues related to the publication of The Prophets. Includes letters from the Prime Minister of Israel's office, Emil Fackenheim, and a review of The Prophets by Samuel Terrien.
      - Prophets, 1963 (Box 155, Folder 4)
        Mix of clippings and printed publications which contain reviews of The Prophets. Also contains the article "The Wrath of God" by Heschel which was printed in Jubilee.
      - Review, 1963; 1 of 2 (Box 155, Folder 5)
        Mix of clippings and printed publications which contain reviews of The Prophets.
      - Review, 1963; 2 of 2 (Box 155, Folder 6)
      - Prophets, 1963-1964 (Box 155, Folder 7)
        Language(s): A few materials in French, Hebrew, and German.
        Mix of correspondence, clippings and printed publications which contain reviews of The Prophets.
      - ha-Doʼar contains "הנביאים", 1964 (Oversize-box 2, Folder 5)
        Transliteration: HaNevi'im
        Translation: The Prophets
        Review of 1962 English-language publication of The Prophets by David Shlomo Shaprio.
      - DE 7-443, circa 1960s; 1 of 6 (Box 156, Folder 1)
        Heavily partial corrected typescript of The Prophets.
      - DE 7-443, circa 1960s; 2 of 6 (Box 156, Folder 2)
      - DE 7-443, circa 1960s; 3 of 6 (Box 156, Folder 3)
      - DE 7-443, circa 1960s; 4 of 6 (Box 156, Folder 4)
      - DE 7-443, circa 1960s; 5 of 6 (Box 156, Folder 5)
      - DE 7-443, circa 1960s; 6 of 6 (Box 156, Folder 6)
      - [Dust jacket cover - The Prophets], circa 1960s (Oversize-box 7, Folder 5)
      - [Galley Proofs - The Prophets], circa 1960s (Oversize-box 6, Folder 6)
        Partial, incomplete galley proofs of The Prophets.
      - [Galley Proofs - The Prophets], circa 1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 157, Folder 1)
        Galley proofs of The Prophets, Volumes 1 and 2, beginning with Chapter 4 of Volume 1.
      - [Galley Proofs - The Prophets], circa 1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - [Galley Proofs - The Prophets], circa 1960s; 3 of 3 (Box 157, Folder 3)
      - Knight Translate, circa 1960s; 1 of 2 (Box 157, Folder 4)
        Clean typescript of the Preface and Parts I and II of the Prophets.
      - Knight Translate, circa 1960s; 2 of 2 (Box 157, Folder 5)
      - Pathos, circa 1960s (Box 157, Folder 6)
        Annotated and corrected typescripts of The Prophets, Volume 2 Chapters 1-5.
      - Postscript: A Note on the Meaning of "Pathos", circa 1960s (Box 157, Folder 7)
        Heavily partial corrected typescript related to pathos.
      - Prophet: Jer, circa 1960s (Box 158, Folder 1)
        Handwritten notes presumably related to the prophet Jeremiah.
      - לא חשוב: Prophet, circa 1960s (Box 158, Folder 2)
        Transliteration: Lo Ḥashuv
        Translation: Not Important
        Primarily handwritten notes related to a variety of topics including justice, injustice, and ecstasy.
      - Prophet, circa 1960s (Box 158, Folder 3)
        Typescripts related to The Prophets. Topics include justice, the divine pathos, and prophecy.
      - Prophets: Justice, circa 1960s (Box 158, Folder 4)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes possibly research material for the chapter on Justice in The Prophets.
      - Prophets, circa 1960s; 1 of 5 (Box 158, Folder 5)
        Annotated typescripts of The Prophets. Includes sections of Volume 1, Chapters 11 and Volume 2 Chapter 1-3 and 15-16.
      - Prophets, circa 1960s; 2 of 5 (Box 158, Folder 6)
      - Prophets, circa 1960s; 3 of 5 (Box 158, Folder 7)
      - Prophets, circa 1960s; 4 of 5 (Box 159, Folder 1)
      - Prophets, circa 1960s; 5 of 5 (Box 159, Folder 2)
      - Prophets I, circa 1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 159, Folder 3)
        Corrected partial typescript of The Prophets.
      - Prophets I, circa 1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 159, Folder 4)
      - Prophets I, circa 1960s; 3 of 3 (Box 159, Folder 5)
      - Prophets II, circa 1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 159, Folder 6)
      - Prophets II, circa 1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 160, Folder 1)
      - Prophets II, circa 1960s; 3 of 3 (Box 160, Folder 2)
      - [The Prophets], circa 1960s (Box 160, Folder 3)
        Partial cut galleys for first 95 pages of The Prophets with occasional corrections.
      - [The Prophets], circa 1960s (Box 160, Folder 4)
        Typescript (pp.418-442), lightly edited by Heschel, of Hebrew translation of The Prophets.
      - [The Prophets], circa 1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 160, Folder 5)
        Typescript (pp.1-140), lightly edited by Heschel, of Hebrew translation of The Prophets.
      - [The Prophets], circa 1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 160, Folder 6)
        Typescript (pp.141-278), lightly edited by Heschel, of Hebrew translation of The Prophets.
      - [The Prophets], circa 1960s; 3 of 3 (Box 160, Folder 7)
        Typescript (pp.279-417), lightly edited by Heschel, of Hebrew translation of The Prophets.
      - To be notarized, circa 1960s; 1 of 2 (Box 161, Folder 1)
        Typescript (pp.227-405), lightly edited by Heschel, of Hebrew translation of The Prophets.
      - To be notarized, circa 1960s; 2 of 2 (Box 161, Folder 2)
      - 3 (313-[404]), undated (Box 161, Folder 3)
        Handwritten manuscript (by Heschel) of Hebrew translation of the The Prophets.
      - 4 (405-475), undated (Box 161, Folder 4)
      - 5 ([517-573]), undated (Box 161, Folder 5)
      - 11 ([476-516]), undated (Box 161, Folder 6)
      - [Analysis of Die Prophetie], undated (Box 161, Folder 7)
        An analysis of Die Prophetie by an unknown author.
      - כוזרי, undated; 1 of 3 (Box 161, Folder 8)
        Transliteration: Kuzari
        Translation: Kuzari
        A typescript version of the handwritten English translation of Die Prophetie.
      - כוזרי, undated; 2 of 3 (Box 161, Folder 9)
      - כוזרי, undated; 3 of 3 (Box 162, Folder 1)
      - שונות: Prophet, undated (Box 162, Folder 2)
        Primarily handwritten notes related to the prophet Jeremiah.
      - Prophet: Out, undated (Box 162, Folder 3)
        Small number of typescripts which have been crossed out with pencil. Possibly removed from the final version of The Prophets.
      - Prophet: Pathos, undated; 1 of 2 (Box 162, Folder 4)
        Primarily handwritten notes related to the topic of pathos. Possibly material for the chapters on Pathos in The Prophets.
      - Prophet: Pathos, undated; 2 of 2 (Box 162, Folder 5)
      - Prophets: Ecstasy, undated (Box 162, Folder 6)
        Mix of handwritten and typed notes possibly research material for the chapters on Ecstasy in The Prophets.
      - Prophets לא חשוב: לא חשוב, Justice, undated (Box 162, Folder 7)
        Handwritten notes and bibliographic references related to The Prophets and the topic of justice.
      - Prophets לא חשוב: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 162, Folder 8)
        Translation: Not important
        A mix of handwritten notes and annotated typescripts related to The Prophets. Topics include justice and prophetic moralism.
      - Prophets לא חשוב: לא כל כך חשוב, undated (Box 162, Folder 9)
        Transliteration: Lo Ḥashuv: Lo kol kakh Ḥashuv
        Translation: Not important: Not so important
        A collection of handwritten notes and bibliographic references related to The Prophets.
      - The Prophets, undated (Box 162, Folder 10)
        Summary of copyright and royalties for The Prophets.
      - [The Prophets], undated (Box 162, Folder 11)
        A typescript of text that is related to but not the same as The Prophets, Volume 2 Chapter 14.
    - The Sabbath, 1951-1998 and undated; 12
      Published by Farrar, Straus and Giroux in 1951. Includes the 15 original engravings used to illustrate the book, 11 of which are signed by Ilya Schor.
      - שבת:שבת IV, circa 1950-1951; 1 of 2 (Box 163, Folder 1)
        Transliteration: Shabat: Shabat
        Translation: Sabbath: Sabbath
        Mostly handwritten notes with some correspondence and annotated typescripts related to The Sabbath. Topics include faith, time, peace, holiness, Rome and labor.
      - שבת:שבת IV, circa 1950-1951; 2 of 2 (Box 163, Folder 2)
      - [Galley Proofs, The Sabbath], 1951; 1 of 2 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 1)
        Annotated galley proofs for The Sabbath.
      - [Galley Proofs, The Sabbath], 1951; 2 of 2 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 2)
      - [Galley Proofs, The Sabbath], 1951; 1 of 2 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 3)
      - [Galley Proofs, The Sabbath], 1951; 2 of 2 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 4)
      - Sabbath, 1951 (Box 163, Folder 3)
        A mix of handwritten notes and correspondence related to the publication of The Sabbath.
      - [Galley Proofs, The Sabbath], circa 1951; 1 of 2 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 5)
      - [Galley Proofs, The Sabbath], circa 1951; 2 of 2 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 6)
      - Woodcuts for The Sabbath, circa 1951 (Oversize-box 8, Folder 11)
        Prints of Ilya Schor's woodcuts that were used to illustrate The Sabbath. Each page includes six images with handwritten chapter/page assignments.
      - Sabbath, 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 4)
        A mix of correspondence and clippings related to the publication of The Sabbath. Includes and annotated typescript of a speech for "RWS."
      - Sabbath, 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 5)
        A mix of event programs, clippings and correspondence from admirers and colleagues related to the publication of The Sabbath. Includes a letter from the Canadian Jewish poet A.M. Klein praising Heschel's English writing style.
      - Sabbath General, 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 6)
        A mix of correspondence and clippings related to the publication of The Sabbath. Includes a copy of the January 5, 1952 issue of Publisher's Weekly which includes mention of The Sabbath in an article about book design by Walter Dorwin Teague.
      - Sabbath Jewish, 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 7)
        A mix of clippings, handwritten notes and correspondence related to the publication of The Sabbath. Includes a reviews of The Sabbath in the March 10, 1952 issue of "Congress Weekly" and the Winter 1952 Issue of The Torch. Also includes a pamphlet, "Reading Aloud from 'The Sabbath: its meaning for Modern Man' by Abraham Joshua Heschel, Suggestions for a reading and discussion program."
      - Sabbath Letters, 1951-1952 (Box 163, Folder 8)
        Language(s): A few materials in Hebrew, Yiddish and German.
        Correspondence from colleagues and admirers in related to the publication of The Sabbath.
      - Sabbath, 1951-1953; 1 of 2 (Box 164, Folder 1)
        A mix of correspondence, handwritten notes and clippings related to the publication of The Sabbath. Includes a review of The Sabbath by Dr. Joseph Kaminetsky in the December 1951 issue of "The Jewish Parents Magazine," an issue of United Synagogue Review which includes an article about The Sabbath, and reviews of both The Sabbath and Man is Not Alone by Mortimer J. Cohen in The Torch and many additional reviews of The Sabbath.
      - Sabbath, 1951-1953; 2 of 2 (Box 164, Folder 2)
      - Account Sabbath, 1951-1956 (Box 164, Folder 3)
        Administrative documents regarding the publication and royalties for The Sabbath. Includes the contract with Farrar, Straus and Young, Inc. for The Sabbath.
      - שבת: No, 1952 (Box 164, Folder 4)
        Handwritten notes and clippings related to The Sabbath. Topics include eternity, time, creation, and labor.
      - Sabbath, 1952 (Box 164, Folder 5)
        Mix of journals, correspondence, reviews, and clippings primarily related to the publication of The Sabbath. Also includes some correspondence and reviews related to Man is Not Alone.
      - שבת IV, circa 1952 (Box 164, Folder 6)
        A mix of handwritten notes and quotes related to The Sabbath. Topics include original sin, the Christian sabbath and Philo.
      - Der Sabbat, 1953 (Box 164, Folder 7)
        German translation of The Sabbath by Curt Rosenthal. Includes and introduction to understanding the book written for the celebration of Leo Baeck's 80th birthday.
      - שבת II, circa 1958 (Box 165, Folder 1)
        Handwritten notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include food, garments and preparation for the sabbath. Includes correspondence related to royalties for the use of Heschel's work in Fritz Rothschild's book.
      - [Dust jacket cover - the Sabbath], circa 1950s (Oversize-box 3, Folder 3)
      - [Galley Proofs - The Sabbath], circa 1950s (Oversize-box 10, Folder 4)
        Galley proofs of The Sabbath.
      - Ilya Schor - Very Important, circa 1950s (Box 165, Folder 2)
        Contains the 15 original wood engravings used to illustrate The Sabbath. 11 are signed by Ilya Schor and some are marked with Heschel's notes related to their chapter assignment. Also includes additional proof-printings of the reproductions, a proof dust jacket and other photographs and related documents.
      - For Lawyer, 1963, 1969, 1971-1972 (Box 165, Folder 3)
        Correspondence regarding reprints of the Abelard-Schuman publications - The Sabbath and The Earth is the Lord's.
      - Time: Time Sent to Rome, 1971 (Box 165, Folder 4)
        A mix of handwritten notes, annotated typescripts and correspondence seemingly related to a translation of The Sabbath. Includes a letter from Elemire Zolla.
      - For Bank Vault, Mrs. Heschel, circa 1998 (Box 165, Folder 5)
        Correspondence related to the value of Ilya Schor's woodcuts and photographs of the flood damage in the Heschel's apartment. Also includes two photographs of Severin Eisenberger, a pianist who taught Sylvia Heschel.
      - שבת: שיריים, undated (Box 165, Folder 6)
        Transliteration: Shabat: Sh'yarim
        Translation: Sabbath: Leftovers
        Handwritten notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include civilization, atmosphere, creation, rest, relaxation, and liturgy. Also includes a bibliography from "Britannica" for the Sabbath.
      - שבת:[Notes], undated (Box 165, Folder 7)
        Handwritten notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include legalism, science, and God.
      - שבת: Sabbath, undated; 1 of 2 (Box 165, Folder 8)
        Contains handwritten notes and typescripts that are mainly the source material for notes in The Sabbath, divided by chapter.
      - שבת: Sabbath, undated; 2 of 2 (Box 165, Folder 9)
      - שבת: Sabbath, undated (Box 165, Folder 10)
        A mix of handwritten notes and annotated typescripts related to The Sabbath. Topics include time, the unique essence, and the sabbath. Includes what is presumable lecture material on Medieval Jewish Philosophy.
      - Ab, undated (Box 165, Folder 11)
        A mix of handwritten notes and annotated typescripts related to The Sabbath. Topics include observance, Jewish ritual, the emerging man and food on the sabbath.
      - שבת, undated (Box 166, Folder 1)
        A mix of handwritten notes and annotated proofs of The Sabbath.
      - שבת, undated (Box 166, Folder 2)
        Handwritten notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include values, history, the soul, chosen people, Jewish crisis, continuity, time and reverence for Israel.
      - שבת, undated (Box 166, Folder 3)
        A mix of handwritten notes and annotated typescripts. Topics include redemption, revelation, nature, the Sabbath within the Decalogue and Israel.
      - שבת, undated; 1 of 3 (Box 166, Folder 4)
        Mostly annotated typescripts of The Sabbath with some handwritten notes.
      - שבת, undated; 2 of 3 (Box 166, Folder 5)
      - שבת, undated; 3 of 3 (Box 166, Folder 6)
      - Spirit - Old Copy, undated (Box 166, Folder 7)
        Handwritten notes and underlined typescripts that appear to be lecture notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include eternity, time, the spirit, success and ritual. Includes annotated and underlined galley proofs of pages 18-32 of The Sabbath.
      - Time: B Time, undated (Box 166, Folder 8)
        A mix of annotated typescripts, lecture notes handwritten notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include time, welcome present, and God.
      - Time: Einstein Olam, undated (Box 167, Folder 1)
        A mix of handwritten notes and annotated typescripts related to The Sabbath. Topics include time, modern man, Einstein and the world.
      - Time: [The Sabbath], undated (Box 167, Folder 2)
        Annotated photocopies typescripts of a few sections of The Sabbath.
      - Time: Time, undated (Box 167, Folder 3)
        A mix of annotated typescripts and handwritten notes related to The Sabbath. Topics include time, eternity, creation, despair and God's presence.
    - Torah min HaShamayim, circa 1950s-1990s and undated; 13
      Volume I and Volume II published in 1962 and 1965 by Soncino Press. Volume III published in 1990 by the Jewish Theological Seminary of America.
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 1 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 1)
        Contains handwritten notes and footnotes, likely for Torah min HaShamayim Vol I.
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 2 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 2)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 3 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 3)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 4 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 4)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 5 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 5)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 6 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 6)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], 1957-1958; 7 of 7 (Box 168, Folder 7)
      - מוסד ביאליק, 1958-1959 (Box 169, Folder 1)
        Transliteration: Mosad Bialik
        Translation: Bilaik Institute
        Contains correspondence concerning the publication of the book Torah min HaShamayim.
      - Torah min Hashamayim, 1959, 1963-1967 (Box 169, Folder 2)
        Correspondence, telegrams, and reports related to the publication, distribution and sale of Torah min HaShamayim.
      - אלו ואלו: מסודר, 1958-1960 (Box 169, Folder 3)
        Transliteration: Elu ṿa-elu: Mesudar
        Translation: Both these words and those ones: Arranged
        Contains handwritten notes about a variety of Jewish topics, including the megilloth, sacrifices, and humankind, in preparation of Volume 3 of Torah min HaShamayim.
      - V דברים, circa 1950s; 1 of 4 (Box 169, Folder 4)
        Transliteration: Devarim
        Translation: Deuteronomy
        Handwritten notes related to Chapter 9 of Torah min HaShamayim Volume 2 on Deuteronomy. The notes are divided into sections, many of which are very close or exactly the same as the section titles in the book.
      - V דברים, circa 1950s; 2 of 4 (Box 169, Folder 5)
      - V דברים, circa 1950s; 3 of 4 (Box 169, Folder 6)
      - V דברים, circa 1950s; 4 of 4 (Box 169, Folder 7)
      - אלדד ומדד, circa 1950s; 1 of 3 (Box 169, Folder 8)
        Transliteration: Eldad u'Medad
        Translation: Eldad and Medad
        Handwritten notes and footnotes, likely for Torah min HaShamayim.
      - אלדד ומדד, circa 1950s; 2 of 3 (Box 170, Folder 1)
      - אלדד ומדד, circa 1950s; 3 of 3 (Box 170, Folder 2)
      - סוף דבר, circa 1950s; 1 of 2 (Box 170, Folder 3)
        Transliteration: Sof Davar
        Translation: Final Thing
        Typescript notes and footnotes, likely for Torah min HaShamayim.
      - סוף דבר, circa 1950s; 2 of 2 (Box 170, Folder 4)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], circa 1950s; 1 of 3 (Box 170, Folder 5)
        Notes and footnotes for Torah min HaShamayim Vol. 2
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], circa 1950s; 2 of 3 (Box 170, Folder 6)
      - [Torah min HaShamayim], circa 1950s; 3 of 3 (Box 170, Folder 7)
      - Torah min [HaShamayim], 1950s-1960s; 1 of 3 (Box 170, Folder 8)
        Contains handwritten and typed notes, mostly about Exodus and revelation.
      - Torah min [HaShamayim], 1950s-1960s; 2 of 3 (Box 171, Folder 1)
      - Torah min [HaShamayim], 1950s-1960s; 3 of 3 (Box 171, Folder 2)
      - תורה מה"ש ח"א, 1960-1965 (Box 171, Folder 3)
        Transliteration: Torah M[in] H[a]"Sh[amayim] ḥ[eleḳ] A[lef]
        Translation: Torah min HaShamayim Part 1
        A mix of handwritten notes, correspondence and annotated typescripts. Includes letters from publishers, Jacob Neusner, and many letters from colleagues and admirers related to the publication of Torah min HaShamayim.
      - [Miscellaneous], 1962 and undated (Box 171, Folder 4)
        Contains preliminary corrected galley proof pages of Torah Min HaShamayim (Ancient Jewish Thought) and handwritten lists of names.
      - תורה מה"ש, א, circa 1962-1965 (Box 171, Folder 5)
        Transliteration: Torah m[in] hash[amaim], a
        Contains mostly reviews of Heschel's book.